

Alex Parejo Creative ideas that make a difference

WEBSITE

alexparejo.com

E-MAIL

alex_parejo@t-online.de

SKYPE

alexparejo@outlook.de

LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/alexparejo

PROFILE

Project Manager with strong knowledge in interdisciplinary technical fields. Specialized in Innovation Projects and responsible for the generation of new ideas, maduration of these into feasible concepts, definition of the technical solution and the development of proof of concepts.

EDUCATION

2013 - now Master of Science

Practical Informatics

Information Systems and Artificial Intelligence

Fernuniversität in Hagen (Germany) Current middle Grade: 1.2 (US GPA: 3.9)

2009 - 2013 Bachelor of Engineering

Electronics and Communications Systems Beuth Hochschule für Technik (Germany)

Grade: 1.8 (US GPA: 3.6)

2005 - 2007 Vocational Education Technical Drafter

I.E.S. Virgen de Consolación (Spain)

2002 - 2004 Vocational Education Automation Technology

I.E.S. Virgen de los Reyes (Spain)

2018 - now **Volkswagen Group Services** Barcelona, Spain

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Leader in the Innovation Department of SEAT

New Technologies, Applications and Electronics Projects

2013 - 2018 **Rücker Lypsa** Barcelona, Spain

Project Leader in the Innovation Department of SEAT

2009 - 2012 Engineering Office Wichmann Berlin, Germany

Technical Drafter of Installationen

2008 - 2009 Randstad Berlin, Germany

Technical Drafter

2008 - 2008 Ayesa Seville, Spain

Technical Drafter on the Project "Cajasol Tower"

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Android-App, C, C++, Java, Flash,

Visual Basic, Matlab, XML, CSS,

HTML, Microcontroller, VHDL, PLC.

Software-tools: AutoCAD, Eagle, LTspice, UML-Tool,

Microsoft Office.

Varied knowledge: Automotives Systems, Electronics,

Telecommunications' Systems.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Spanish: **Native**

German: Fluent

English: Fair

Italian: **Basic**

ADITIONAL INFORMATION

Continuing education:

-Project Management course

-Introduction to Marketing course

-Design Thinking for Innovation course

-CAN-BUS course

Currently - Fernuniversität in Hagen, Alemania

2018 – University of Pennsylvania, USA (Coursera – no certificate)

2017 – University of Virginia, USA (Coursera – no certificate)

2015 - Rücker-Lypsa

Patents and patents pending:

- -Spain (P201530860) / Germany (DE10201610210488): Method for detection of the position of a parked vehicle.
- -Spain (P201630791): Method for creation of a text message for an electronic device in a vehicle.
- -Spain (P201731119): Method and system for displaying virtual reality information in a vehicle.
- -Spain (P201731120): Method and system for displaying priority information on a vehicle.
- -Spain (P201731121): Method and system for displaying virtual reality information in a vehicle.
- -Spain (P201731163): Method for determining compatibility between users in a shared vehicle.